<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Main on Zakhar the Robot</title><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/</link><description>Recent content in Main on Zakhar the Robot</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/docs/architecture/phase1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/docs/architecture/phase1/</guid><description>Architecture - Phase 1 # Introduction and Goals # The goal of the Phase 1 is to establish the main back borne of the future architecture and the main principles of the project.
This documentation uses some parts of the https://arc42.org architecture documentation framework, but lacks some mandatory sections in sake of simplicity and development progress.
Architecture Constraints # Architecture relies on usage of Robot Operating System (ROS). It is expected that ROS will provide access to a large and relevant library of software components during the next iterations and simple communications between nodes.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/docs/systems/brain/ros_install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/docs/systems/brain/ros_install/</guid><description>ROS instalation # At the time of summer 2020 there is no way to install noetic on Raspberry Pi OS. That&amp;rsquo;s why we will build it manually
ROS Noetic build # Step 1 — Set up ROS Noetic repo on Raspberry Pi 4 # 1 sudo sh -c &amp;#39;echo &amp;#34;deb http://packages.ros.org/ros/ubuntu buster main&amp;#34; &amp;gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/ros-noetic.list&amp;#39; Step 2 — Add official ROS key # 1 sudo apt-key adv --keyserver &amp;#39;hkp://keyserver.ubuntu.com:80&amp;#39; --recv-key C1CF6E31E6BADE8868B172B4F42ED6FBAB17C654 Step 3 — Pull all meta info of ROS Noetic packages # 1 sudo apt update Step 4 — Install build dependencies on Raspberry Pi 4 # 1 sudo apt-get install -y python-rosdep python-rosinstall-generator python-wstool python-rosinstall build-essential cmake Step 5 — Set up ROS Noetic dependency sources/repos # 1 2 sudo rosdep init rosdep update Step 6 — Fetch &amp;amp; Install ROS Noetic dependencies # 1 2 3 4 5 mkdir ~/ros_catkin_ws cd ~/ros_catkin_ws rosinstall_generator ros_comm --rosdistro noetic --deps --wet-only --tar &amp;gt; noetic-ros_comm-wet.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/for_developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/doc/for_developers/</guid><description>For Developers # The project is ambitious, and I cannot move it that fast as I want to. If you are as interested in robotics as I am, let&amp;rsquo;s try to work together. I&amp;rsquo;m confident that we will develop something unique.
The project covers many different areas and programming languages, including:
3D modeling (for simulation) 3D printing (for the robot itself) C / C ++ development (embedded: Arduino, ESP32, STM32; hi-level: Linux, Robot Operating System - ROS) Computer vision (image recognition, especially for indoor navigation) Hardware design (robot modules) Python development (Robot Operating System - ROS) Please look at the list of repositories and active projects below, see the issues, and take something if you want.</description></item></channel></rss>