<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Zakhar the Robot</title><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Zakhar the Robot</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/canbus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/canbus/</guid><description>ZakharCAN (ver. 0.0.0) # The standard is based on the CAN bus protocol. Base CAN configuration:
Bitrate: 125 kbits/s ID: 11 bits In the standard there are several common parameters:
Common timeout: 3 sec Dev ID size: 3 bits Data ID size: 4 bits Addressing # Each device uses 3 highest bits of the 11-bit ID for it&amp;rsquo;s ID (0..7). The last 4 bits are used for different data types (0.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/devices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/devices/</guid><description>Devices # Back to README
The main node - it is the node containing main operational program if the robot. Currently it is Raspberry Pi 4.
Zakhar has three devices connected to the main node:
The Face Module - responsible for expressions and interaction with the user The Moving Platform - responsible for movement The Sensor Platform - responsible for perception Each device stores data into registers and interacts with the main node via I2C (i2c conventions used in the project are here)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/future/</guid><description>Future plans # Detailed plans of the project development:
✅ Reptile Demo - implementing of a simple reptile instinct Article: Robot with the Conscious: Imitating animal behavior for reducing user’s anxiety ✅ Zakharos - moving the core to the ROS 🟧 Emotions Demo - emotions and reflexes New Features: [wip] Implementing Emotions - behavior modificators, the more Conditioned response taught, the worse mood in response to the darkness Claustrophobia - freeze and shiver if closed barrier and dark (instinct, unconditioned response) Conditioned response - growing amount of claustrophobia situations leads to afraid the darkness, connecting darkness with claustrophobia ✅ HW update: Add a distance sensor to The Sensor platform.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/i2c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zakhar-the-robot.github.io/site/docs/i2c/</guid><description>ZakharI2C # Back to README
This file describes I2C communication used by Zakhar&amp;rsquo;s systems
Basic description # Standard uses 7-bit addressing. Devices can have data located in 0x02&amp;hellip;0xFE registers - 253 bytes Each device mandatorily has registers 0x00 to store command, 0x01 for arguments, and 0x02 to store device state. Commands should be represented by values 0x01&amp;hellip;0xFE Read and write operations are described bellow Registers # Minimal register map:</description></item></channel></rss>